<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music on nikblogs</title>
    <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music on nikblogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.niksethi.com/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JQBX.fm and Live Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/live-collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/live-collaboration/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I would pop onto a website called turntable.fm, where you could pick a cute little avatar to represent yourself in a room and choose to either be a DJ and play music for the room or just vibe as a listener. As a DJ, you could pick from songs from an existing catalog or upload your own, which made the service popular with DJs like Diplo. With each song, every person in the room had the option to vote on whether or not they liked the song, a form of instant feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playlist Log: solitary summer</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/playlist-log-solitary-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/playlist-log-solitary-summer/</guid>
      <description>I spent a lot of summers listening to deeply depressing music by Sufjan Stevens, Frank Ocean, and The Antlers, among others. For the brightest months of the year, I would be buried under a cloud of sad. Eventually, I graduated high school, and started to find more joy in my summers (I made some friends!). Classic summer music suddenly was more appealing than ever, and I got into the habit of making summer playlists to announce my love of the sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jammin&#39; with Niknaps and KTastrophe</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/jammin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/jammin/</guid>
      <description>This weekend, KT and I spent some time just vibing in Ableton, thanks to their extended free trial for the time of COVID-19. With the software and a MIDI keyboard borrowed from the ever-gracious AIR APPARENT (my much more musical brother), we were ready to BUILD.
We focused on recreating some songs from scratch: first MGMT’s “Electric Feel” and Ivy Lab’s “Jet Lag.” Being able to learn how to use the tools without having to also generate new tunes made the big scary app seem more accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>