<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nikblogs</title>
    <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on nikblogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.niksethi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An American Writer for an Age of Division by Alexandra Schwartz [Article Commentary]</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/ayad-akhtar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/ayad-akhtar/</guid>
      <description>I used to regularly add my commentary to articles on my tumblr as I read, as a way to track what I read and just reflect on what I was consuming. Let&amp;rsquo;s try that again
Link to Original Piece
This is an absolutely killer profile of a Pakistani-American writer named Ayad Akhtar that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about. Reading it was a thrill, for standard &amp;ldquo;representation reasons,&amp;rdquo; since it&amp;rsquo;s rare to see multiple identities of mine (Punjabi + writer + strong fascination with religion) line up with anyone I see on a big stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Yourself</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/know-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/know-yourself/</guid>
      <description>What does it mean to know yourself? Is it uncovering a unique set of views or ideas or beliefs that exist independently of any external influence? That is, is anything about me my own creation, or am I fully a product of the world I was born and raised in? And so, is it ever possible to fully know myself, or can I just figure out a set of preferences that were subconsciously formed at the intersection of people, culture, and community in my life?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health and Wellness in Society (TWOS Days 4)</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/08-13-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/08-13-20/</guid>
      <description>I took today and tomorrow off from work. Lately, I’ve been finding it really difficult to focus at work, so I decided to give myself a nice four day weekend to reset and relax.
Today was one of the best days I’ve had in a while. I lazily woke up around 8 or 9, heated up an extra cup of chai from the fridge (not great, and just spent an hour or so on my phone, but not in a doomscrolling way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writerly Ambition (TWOS Days 2 and 3)</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/08-12-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/08-12-20/</guid>
      <description>I’m 30 minutes into this video of the Sami people herding reindeer across the Arctic. Apparently, reindeer are considered partially domesticated due to indigenous people like the Sami who continue to rely on reindeer herding for survival. I ended up doing more research on domesticated animals in general. The Wikipedia page has a “purposes” section for each animal that was domesticated through history. It’s interesting to see because as time goes, domestication goes from being something that is highly purposeful, with animals like dogs, goats and cattle, to something that’s not, like hedgehogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear and Music (TWOS Day 1)</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/08-10-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/08-10-20/</guid>
      <description>There’s a weeklong #1000wordsofsummer challenge happening. Usually, these challenges are 14 days long, which feels impossible to even attempt. But seven days seems doable, especially since I have so few other responsibilities these days.
In all honesty, I’m not doing great. 23 hasn’t really been the most fun so far. I feel somewhat like the world feels: unstable and unclear. When I was younger, I associated getting older with feeling more in command, as each subsequent year was associated with new privileges to get used to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JQBX.fm and Live Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/live-collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/live-collaboration/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I would pop onto a website called turntable.fm, where you could pick a cute little avatar to represent yourself in a room and choose to either be a DJ and play music for the room or just vibe as a listener. As a DJ, you could pick from songs from an existing catalog or upload your own, which made the service popular with DJs like Diplo. With each song, every person in the room had the option to vote on whether or not they liked the song, a form of instant feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Figuring Things Out</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/figuring-things-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/figuring-things-out/</guid>
      <description>After growing up in a house with a lot of rules and spending little time outside of it, I found myself loving the idea of not having commitments. Without commitments, any chunk of time is for whatever I want. My whims can choose where the time goes. Not anyone else, except for me. Even as I work a full-time job, I wonder what it would be like to find a more autonomous gig, where I wouldn’t even be bound by location or 9-5 expectations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playlist Log: solitary summer</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/playlist-log-solitary-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/playlist-log-solitary-summer/</guid>
      <description>I spent a lot of summers listening to deeply depressing music by Sufjan Stevens, Frank Ocean, and The Antlers, among others. For the brightest months of the year, I would be buried under a cloud of sad. Eventually, I graduated high school, and started to find more joy in my summers (I made some friends!). Classic summer music suddenly was more appealing than ever, and I got into the habit of making summer playlists to announce my love of the sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Loss of my College Twitter Community</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/twitter-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/twitter-community/</guid>
      <description>This month, most of my friends still in school graduated, making me realize that it’s been over a year since I got out. What a strange thing. After graduation, I spent 6 weeks at home: job searching, job acquiring, and then packing to uproot my life and move across the country to a city where I barely knew anyone. As I thought about the unknown world on the Left Coast, I decided to try and use Twitter to avoid feeling too isolated in my new life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Side Characters</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/side-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/side-characters/</guid>
      <description>I used to read a lot of fantasy books and would love to get lost in the lore. I loved to learn about the edges of each world, just beyond the main story. Like yes, I would love to learn more about the random village hundreds of miles away from the objective of this book. Books with maps like the Inheritance series or the Merlin Saga were a delight! I would love flipping to the map just to trace out the journey of the characters, and try to figure out where they would go next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jammin&#39; with Niknaps and KTastrophe</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/jammin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/jammin/</guid>
      <description>This weekend, KT and I spent some time just vibing in Ableton, thanks to their extended free trial for the time of COVID-19. With the software and a MIDI keyboard borrowed from the ever-gracious AIR APPARENT (my much more musical brother), we were ready to BUILD.
We focused on recreating some songs from scratch: first MGMT’s “Electric Feel” and Ivy Lab’s “Jet Lag.” Being able to learn how to use the tools without having to also generate new tunes made the big scary app seem more accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new blog (again)</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/new-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;warning, this blog entry has a lot of terribly boring platform/app talk that you can probably skim through or skip entirely. i promise that future versions won’t be like this. thanks, love you!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
