<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on nikblogs</title>
    <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on nikblogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.niksethi.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JQBX.fm and Live Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/live-collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/live-collaboration/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I would pop onto a website called turntable.fm, where you could pick a cute little avatar to represent yourself in a room and choose to either be a DJ and play music for the room or just vibe as a listener. As a DJ, you could pick from songs from an existing catalog or upload your own, which made the service popular with DJs like Diplo. With each song, every person in the room had the option to vote on whether or not they liked the song, a form of instant feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Figuring Things Out</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/figuring-things-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/figuring-things-out/</guid>
      <description>After growing up in a house with a lot of rules and spending little time outside of it, I found myself loving the idea of not having commitments. Without commitments, any chunk of time is for whatever I want. My whims can choose where the time goes. Not anyone else, except for me. Even as I work a full-time job, I wonder what it would be like to find a more autonomous gig, where I wouldn’t even be bound by location or 9-5 expectations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playlist Log: solitary summer</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/playlist-log-solitary-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/playlist-log-solitary-summer/</guid>
      <description>I spent a lot of summers listening to deeply depressing music by Sufjan Stevens, Frank Ocean, and The Antlers, among others. For the brightest months of the year, I would be buried under a cloud of sad. Eventually, I graduated high school, and started to find more joy in my summers (I made some friends!). Classic summer music suddenly was more appealing than ever, and I got into the habit of making summer playlists to announce my love of the sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Loss of my College Twitter Community</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/twitter-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/twitter-community/</guid>
      <description>This month, most of my friends still in school graduated, making me realize that it’s been over a year since I got out. What a strange thing. After graduation, I spent 6 weeks at home: job searching, job acquiring, and then packing to uproot my life and move across the country to a city where I barely knew anyone. As I thought about the unknown world on the Left Coast, I decided to try and use Twitter to avoid feeling too isolated in my new life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Side Characters</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/side-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/side-characters/</guid>
      <description>I used to read a lot of fantasy books and would love to get lost in the lore. I loved to learn about the edges of each world, just beyond the main story. Like yes, I would love to learn more about the random village hundreds of miles away from the objective of this book. Books with maps like the Inheritance series or the Merlin Saga were a delight! I would love flipping to the map just to trace out the journey of the characters, and try to figure out where they would go next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jammin&#39; with Niknaps and KTastrophe</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/jammin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/jammin/</guid>
      <description>This weekend, KT and I spent some time just vibing in Ableton, thanks to their extended free trial for the time of COVID-19. With the software and a MIDI keyboard borrowed from the ever-gracious AIR APPARENT (my much more musical brother), we were ready to BUILD.
We focused on recreating some songs from scratch: first MGMT’s “Electric Feel” and Ivy Lab’s “Jet Lag.” Being able to learn how to use the tools without having to also generate new tunes made the big scary app seem more accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new blog (again)</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/new-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;warning, this blog entry has a lot of terribly boring platform/app talk that you can probably skim through or skip entirely. i promise that future versions won’t be like this. thanks, love you!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>