<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>creativity on nikblogs</title>
    <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/tags/creativity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in creativity on nikblogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.niksethi.com/tags/creativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An American Writer for an Age of Division by Alexandra Schwartz [Article Commentary]</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/ayad-akhtar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/ayad-akhtar/</guid>
      <description>I used to regularly add my commentary to articles on my tumblr as I read, as a way to track what I read and just reflect on what I was consuming. Let&amp;rsquo;s try that again
Link to Original Piece
This is an absolutely killer profile of a Pakistani-American writer named Ayad Akhtar that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about. Reading it was a thrill, for standard &amp;ldquo;representation reasons,&amp;rdquo; since it&amp;rsquo;s rare to see multiple identities of mine (Punjabi + writer + strong fascination with religion) line up with anyone I see on a big stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writerly Ambition (TWOS Days 2 and 3)</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/08-12-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/08-12-20/</guid>
      <description>I’m 30 minutes into this video of the Sami people herding reindeer across the Arctic. Apparently, reindeer are considered partially domesticated due to indigenous people like the Sami who continue to rely on reindeer herding for survival. I ended up doing more research on domesticated animals in general. The Wikipedia page has a “purposes” section for each animal that was domesticated through history. It’s interesting to see because as time goes, domestication goes from being something that is highly purposeful, with animals like dogs, goats and cattle, to something that’s not, like hedgehogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear and Music (TWOS Day 1)</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/08-10-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/08-10-20/</guid>
      <description>There’s a weeklong #1000wordsofsummer challenge happening. Usually, these challenges are 14 days long, which feels impossible to even attempt. But seven days seems doable, especially since I have so few other responsibilities these days.
In all honesty, I’m not doing great. 23 hasn’t really been the most fun so far. I feel somewhat like the world feels: unstable and unclear. When I was younger, I associated getting older with feeling more in command, as each subsequent year was associated with new privileges to get used to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JQBX.fm and Live Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/live-collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/live-collaboration/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I would pop onto a website called turntable.fm, where you could pick a cute little avatar to represent yourself in a room and choose to either be a DJ and play music for the room or just vibe as a listener. As a DJ, you could pick from songs from an existing catalog or upload your own, which made the service popular with DJs like Diplo. With each song, every person in the room had the option to vote on whether or not they liked the song, a form of instant feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jammin&#39; with Niknaps and KTastrophe</title>
      <link>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/jammin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.niksethi.com/post/jammin/</guid>
      <description>This weekend, KT and I spent some time just vibing in Ableton, thanks to their extended free trial for the time of COVID-19. With the software and a MIDI keyboard borrowed from the ever-gracious AIR APPARENT (my much more musical brother), we were ready to BUILD.
We focused on recreating some songs from scratch: first MGMT’s “Electric Feel” and Ivy Lab’s “Jet Lag.” Being able to learn how to use the tools without having to also generate new tunes made the big scary app seem more accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
